A Guide to the Joseph Francis Fletcher Papers (1931-1991)
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Reviews: Review of Morals and Medicine, 1964 July (Box-folder 030:002)
- Reviews: Reviews and Criticisms of Situation Ethics, 1966 January 21-1966 July-August, 65 Items (Box-folder 030:003)
- Reviews: Reviews and Criticisms of Situation Ethics, 1966 August 15-1968 December, N.D., 77 Items (Box-folder 030:004)
- Reviews: Reviews of Moral Responsibility, 1967 February 15-1969 January, N.D., 6 Items (Box-folder 030:005)
- Reviews: Kenneth Curtis to Westminster Press, with review of Moral Responsibility, 1967 March 23, 2 Items (Box-folder 030:006)
- Reviews: Review of The Situation Ethics Debate, 1968 October (Box-folder 030:007)
- Reviews: Review of Storm Over Ethics, 1969 Winter (Box-folder 030:008)
- Reviews: Reviews of Humanhood: Essays in Biomedical Ethics, 1979 May 19, 1980 April, 2 Items (Box-folder 030:009)
- Reviews: Review of The Ethics of Genetic Control: Ending Reproductive Roulette, 1989 January 20 (Box-folder 030:010)
- Reviews: Paper by David P. Bennett discussing "Humanism and Theism in Biomedical Ethics," 1990 January 25 (Box-folder 030:011)
- Sermons, Fletcher: untitled, preached at the Episcopal Theological School, 1966 April 19 (Box-folder 030:012)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Let's Be Done With Religion," 1967 February 26 (Box-folder 030:013)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Easter," 1968 April 4 (Box-folder 030:014)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "The Advent of Love," N.D. (Box-folder 030:015)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Arise and Stand Upon Thy Feet," N.D. (Box-folder 030:016)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Being Holy," N.D. (Box-folder 030:017)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "The Birth of Love," N.D. (Box-folder 030:018)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Christian Encounter with Non-Christians," N.D. (Box-folder 030:019)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Christianity Not Religion," N.D. (Box-folder 030:020)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Ethics as Vocation, Not Salvation," N.D. (Box-folder 030:021)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Giving Evil the Help It Needs," N.D. (Box-folder 030:022)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "The Good Samaritan," N.D. (Box-folder 030:023)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "The Iceberg Sermon," N.D. (Box-folder 030:024)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Is Christ Divided?" N.D. (Box-folder 030:025)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Law is Like Slavery," N.D. (Box-folder 030:026)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Man on a Cross," N.D. (Box-folder 030:027)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Ministry of the Laity," N.D. (Box-folder 030:028)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Noboru Iwamura," N.D. (Box-folder 030:029)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Pinocchio - The Pattern of Salvation," N.D. (Box-folder 030:030)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Suffering - The Book of Job," N.D. (Box-folder 030:031)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Two Kinds of Christians," N.D. (Box-folder 030:032)
- Sermons, Fletcher: "Unity of Mankind," N.D. (Box-folder 030:033)
- Sermons, Fletcher: untitled, N.D., 2 Items (Box-folder 030:034)
- Sermons, Fletcher: untitled sermon on Romans 13:8, N.D. (Box-folder 030:035)
- Sermons, Fletcher: miscellaneous notes, N.D. (Box-folder 030:036)
- Sermons: Three Sermons Concerning Joseph Fletcher, 1967 June 4-1968 November 17, 3 Items (Box-folder 030:037)
- World Peace Movement: Soviet-American Relations Pamphlet, 1946 October 11 (Box-folder 031:001)
- World Peace Movement: "The Bishops on Social Problems, 1937-1947," 1947 (Box-folder 031:002)
- World Peace Movement: Edward Eli Curtis to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 May 21 (Box-folder 031:003)
- World Peace Movement: Don Gross to [Joseph Fletcher], 1950 January 5 (Box-folder 031:004)
- World Peace Movement: Betty Hirschfelder to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 April 12 (Box-folder 031:005)
- World Peace Movement: Correspondence of Joseph Shanahan with Hewlett Johnson and Joseph Stalin, and related materials, (carbon copies), 1950 April 14, 26, 5 Items (Box-folder 031:006)
- World Peace Movement: B. B. Chapman to Joseph Fletcher, [1950] April 17 (Box-folder 031:007)
- World Peace Movement: Lorna Hay to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 April 18 (Box-folder 031:008)
- World Peace Movement: William John Morrison to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 April 20 (Box-folder 031:009)
- World Peace Movement: W. Bird to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 April 26 (Box-folder 031:010)
- World Peace Movement: Fred S. Spillman to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1950 April 28, 3 Items (Box-folder 031:011)
- World Peace Movement: Address by Dr. Hewlett Johnson, Dean of Canterbury, for the Australian Peace Congress, 1950 April 30 (Box-folder 031:012)
- World Peace Movement: International Red Cross Statement on Outlawing Atomic Weapons, 1950 April, 4 Items (Box-folder 031:013)
- World Peace Movement: Materials concerning the Australian Peace Congress, 1950 April, 13 Items (Box-folder 031:014)
- World Peace Movement: Jessie M. G. Street to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 June 7 (Box-folder 031:015)
- World Peace Movement: Joseph Fletcher to Ralph Harlow, 1950 June (Box-folder 031:016)
- World Peace Movement: copy of form letter from Francis H. Russell, with enclosure and rebuttal, 1950 July 27, N.D., 3 Items (Box-folder 031:017)
- World Peace Movement: [Frederic] Joliot-Curie to Joseph Fletcher, with attached notes, 1950 July 28, 5 Items (Box-folder 031:018)
- World Peace Movement: Frederic Joliot-Curie to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure and envelope, 1950 July 31, 3 Items (Box-folder 031:019)
- World Peace Movement: Elizabeth to Joseph Fletcher, with envelope, [1950] August 5, 2 Items (Box-folder 031:020)
- World Peace Movement: Josef Rybar to Joseph Fletcher, with envelope, 1950 August 9, 2 Items (Box-folder 031:021)
- World Peace Movement: address by Joseph Fletcher, Ostrava, 1950 August 18 (Box-folder 031:022)
- World Peace Movement: A. J. Muste to William E. Foley, 1950 August 29 (Box-folder 031:023)
- World Peace Movement: petition forms, Committee for Peaceful Alternatives, Peace Information Center, 1950 August, N.D., 2 Items (Box-folder 031:024)
- World Peace Movement: "Developments in Moscow's 'Signatures for Peace' Campaign," 1950 September (Box-folder 031:025)
- World Peace Movement: Father [Joseph Fletcher, Sr.] to Joe [Joseph Fletcher, Jr.], with enclosures, [1950] October 1, 4 Items (Box-folder 031:026)
- World Peace Movement: Herbert Johnson to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 October 8 (Box-folder 031:027)
- World Peace Movement: notice for lecture by Joseph Fletcher, 1950 October 26 (Box-folder 031:028)
- World Peace Movement: "The Stockholm Appeal," in Our Common Concern, vol. 2, no. 1, 1950 October, 2 Items (Box-folder 031:029)
- World Peace Movement: Robert M. Muir to American Delegates to Second World Peace Congress, 1950 November 7 (Box-folder 031:030)
- World Peace Movement: Frank Nagy to Joseph Fletcher, with envelope and enclosed essay, 1950 November 10, 3 Items (Box-folder 031:031)
- World Peace Movement: reception invitation for World Peace Congress delegates, 1950 November 10 (Box-folder 031:032)
- World Peace Movement: address by Joseph Fletcher for the Second World Congress for Peace, 1950 Nobember 16-22 (Box-folder 031:033)
- World Peace Movement: Second World Peace Congress brochure, 1950 November 16-22 (Box-folder 031:034)
- World Peace Movement: Margaret H. Barber to Hewlett Johnson?, 1950 November 19 (Box-folder 031:035)
- World Peace Movement: "Sign Here, Comrade!" Ivo Duchacek, This Week Magazine, 1950 November 26 (Box-folder 031:036)
- World Peace Movement: address by [Joseph Fletcher], Bates College, 1950 December 8 (Box-folder 031:037)
- World Peace Movement: [Joseph Fletcher] to Appie, 1950 December 9 (Box-folder 031:038)
- World Peace Movement: George Sarton to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 December 9 (Box-folder 031:039)
- World Peace Movement: Robert D. Seward to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 December 10 (Box-folder 031:040)
- World Peace Movement: Arthur H. Daiken to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 December 16 (Box-folder 031:041)
- World Peace Movement: Czechoslovak Committee to World Peace Committee, New York, 1950 December 31 (Box-folder 031:042)
- World Peace Movement: address by Wu Hsiu-Chuan, "People's China Stands for Peace," 1950 December (Box-folder 031:043)
- World Peace Movement: anonymous to Joseph Fletcher, [1950 December] (Box-folder 031:044)
- World Peace Movement: National Committee for Peaceful Alternatives Brochure, 1950 December (Box-folder 031:045)
- World Peace Movement: [ ] D. Adams to Joseph Fletcher, [1950] (Box-folder 031:046)
- World Peace Movement: John to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], [1950] (Box-folder 031:047)
- World Peace Movement: "Let's Join the Human Race," Stringfellow Barr, 1950 (Box-folder 031:048)
- World Peace Movement: newspaper clipping scrapbook, with notes by [Joseph Fletcher], 1950 (Box-folder 031:049)
- World Peace Movement: World Peace Appeal brochures, [1950], 2 Items (Box-folder 031:050)
- World Peace Movement: World Peace Council Members, biographies and photographs, [1950], 11 Items (Box-folder 031:051)
- World Peace Movement: Bob Woodroofe to Joseph Fletcher, with attached newspaper clipping, 1951 January 4, 2 Items (Box-folder 031:052)
- World Peace Movement: draft response by Joseph Fletcher to Church Militant editors, 1951 January 6 (Box-folder 031:053)
- World Peace Movement: address by O. Frederick Nolde, "Moral Requirements in a Three-Pronged Peace Offensive," 1951 January 8 (Box-folder 031:054)
- World Peace Movement: David R. Hunter to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 January 9 (Box-folder 031:055)
- World Peace Movement: Bob Woodroofe to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], 1951 January 9 (Box-folder 031:056)
- World Peace Movement: address by Joseph Fletcher, Chicago, 1951 January 12 (Box-folder 031:057)
- World Peace Movement: Lafitte to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 January 16 (Box-folder 031:058)
- World Peace Movement: [Joseph Fletcher] to Amory, 1951 January 17 (Box-folder 031:059)
- World Peace Movement: David R. Hunter to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], [1951] January 23 (Box-folder 031:060)
- World Peace Movement: "Communism Exposed," Cornelius Dalton, with related newspaper clippings and notes by [Joseph Fletcher], 1951 January 26, N.D., 4 Items (Box-folder 031:061)
- World Peace Movement: Burdette Landsdowne to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], 1951 February 18 (Box-folder 031:062)
- World Peace Movement: Ellen to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], 1951 February 23 (Box-folder 031:063)
- World Peace Movement: Bill Hackney to Joseph Fletcher, [1951] February 24 (Box-folder 031:064)
- World Peace Movement: Robert Miller to the Editorial Board, The Church Militant, 1951 February 24 (Box-folder 031:065)
- World Peace Movement: Richard A. Strong to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1951 February 25, 2 Items (Box-folder 031:066)
- World Peace Movement: Samuel A. Campbell to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 February 26 (Box-folder 031:067)
- World Peace Movement: Edward Price to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 February 26 (Box-folder 031:068)
- World Peace Movement: "Dr. Fletcher Answers Some Questions, The Church Militant, vol. LIV, no. 2, 1951 February (Box-folder 031:069)
- World Peace Movement: [Joseph Fletcher] to Ben Hibbs, with Saturday Evening Post article, "Did Stalin Make a Sucker Out of You?" and response by [Fletcher], 1951 May 17, 3 Items (Box-folder 031:070)
- World Peace Movement: subpoena for Joseph Fletcher, for U.S. District Court Testimony, 1951 November 20 (Box-folder 031:071)
- World Peace Movement: C. W. Chandler to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 December 2 (Box-folder 031:072)
- World Peace Movement: subpoena for Joseph Fletcher, for Senate testimony, and revocation, 1953 March 23, 24, 2 Items (Box-folder 031:073)
- World Peace Movement: Sam McCain to [Joseph Fletcher], 1953 April 9 (Box-folder 031:074)
- World Peace Movement: "Christianity and Communism", George Carpenter, N.D. (Box-folder 031:075)
- World Peace Movement: notes, N.D., 1 Item (Box-folder 031:076)
- World Peace Movement: statement by Episcopal Theological School Faculty, N.D. (Box-folder 031:077)
- Three Scrapbooks ca. 1930-1958 (Box-folder 032:000)
- Photographs, Plaques, and Posters various (Box-folder 033:000)
- Fred E. Sams to Joseph Fletcher, enclosing the Joseph Fletcher Lawyers' Conference proceedings: "The Rise of Global Fundamentalism"1989 May 31, 2 Items (Box-folder 034:001)
- Kenneth Vaux to Joseph Fletcher, enclosing draft manuscript: "Ethics in Situ: Clinical and Situational Ethics, essays in honor of Joseph Fletcher", and notes by Fletcher. 1989 September 25, N.D., 3 Items (Box-folder 034:002)
- Manuscript drafts (chapters 1 and 5) for an unidentified publication, N.D., 2 Items (Box-folder 034:003)
- Miscellaneous Essays N.D., 6 Items (Box-folder 034:004)
- "Morals and Consequences," by Joseph Fletcher (two drafts, incomplete, never published?), N.D., 3 Items (Box-folder 034:005)
- "PKU Catch 22" manuscript draft, N.D. (Box-folder 034:006)
- Pleadings, Exhibits, and Judgment in the case of York v. Jones, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Virginia, Norfolk Division, concerning in vitro fertilization and ownership of embryo, 1989 July 10, N.D., 5 Items (Box-folder 035:001)
- Various Printed Documents, 1955 April-1967 January 12, N.D., 12 Items (Box-folder 035:002)
- Report of the Dean to the Board of Trustees, Episcopal Theological School, 1962 (Box-folder 035:003)
- Various Press Releases, [1964]-1969 March 26, N.D., 7 Items (Box-folder 035:004)
- Memoranda to Episcopal Theological School Administration, concerning curriculum and a faculty ethics appointment, 1969 April 7, 8, 2 Items (Box-folder 035:005)
- Student Papers, 1948 January-1958 October 22, N.D., 8 Items (Box-folder 035:006)
- Dissertation proposal and Notes regarding Fletcher and ethics, 1969 May 5-1990 September 6, 2 Items (Box-folder 035:007)